汉克葛林全球投资
美国纽约市百老街230号
混蛋
Son of a bitch!
比尔·莫里斯
年度最佳业务员
救命解药
我们不能动市政债券
No, we can't touch the munis.
我们要利用这些债券
We'll use them as collateral for a leveraged
作为思科融资股权的担保品
equity position in Cisco.
预测报表 寻找更新
然后把钱从第一银行移到拜恩
Then I want you to take everything out of First National and move it over to Banyon.
等等 你是说达拉瓦
Wait, you mean Delaware?
我以为那早就没了
I thought that was dead.
重新启动了
That's resurrected.
我们得漂白雷诺斯的帐户
We need to clean up the Reynolds account...
以免洗钱防治单位的混蛋来调查
in case those fucks at AML decide to do their job.
你确定
Are you sure about this?
不要用电邮联络
Nothing on email.
星期一把钱都挪回来
Move everything back on Monday.
你有在听吗
You paying attention?
有 我有
Yeah, yeah, I am.
- 查票 - 我不知道
- Tickets? - I don't know if...
我正在传数字过去
I'm sending the numbers through now.
那葛林怎么办
What about Green?
拖延他 谁管啊 必要就请病假
Uh, stall him. I don't give a shit. Call in sick if you have to.
你是洽公还是旅游
Business or pleasure?
我不知道
I don't know. I just...
你认真的
Seriously?
我不知道这样好不好
Look, I don't know if I feel comfortable...
贾许 别再孬了
Josh! Josh! Stop being such a pussy.
照表说的去办 完成后打给我
Just do what I tell you to do, and call me when it's done.
致董事会同仁
To my fellow members of the board.
人无法忽视真相
A man cannot unsee the truth.
一旦看见光明
He cannot willingly return to darkness...
就不可能自愿回归黑晴或选择失明
or go blind once he has the gift of sight...
就如同无法回到未出生时
any more than he can be unborn.
人类是唯一能自表反省的物种
We are the only species capable of self-reflection.
只有人类的基因密码
The only species with the toxin of self-doubt
编写了自我怀疑的毒素
written into our genetic code.
跟天赋不对等的是
Unequal to our gifts,
我们会创造 购买 消耗
we build, we buy, we consume.
我们以物质成功的假象包装自我
We wrap ourselves in the illusion of material success.
我们欺骗隐瞒 一路往上爬
We cheat and deceive as we claw our way...
到达所谓成统的巅峰
to the pinnacle of what we define as achievement.
对其他人产生优越感
Superiority to other men.
角落办公室
Corner office.
你是替谁吹喇叭换来的
Who'd you have to blow?
我听说他搞定了雷诺斯的帐户
I heard he closed the Reynolds account.
你到底是怎么办到的
How exactly did you do that?
算我实力坚强吧
Just that good, I guess.
别忘了我扪这些小咖
Don't forget about us little people.
我哪会
Oh, how could I?
你知道我的咖啡要加什么
You know how I take my coffee.
抱歉 上头请你到董事会议室
Excuse me, but they wanna see you upstairs in the partners boardroom.
跟他们说我马上过去
Tell them I'll be right there.
明天是你妈的生日
Oh, and tomorrow is your mother's birthday.
替我买个礼物给她
Get her something for me, would you?
没问题
Of course.
人的内在充满病态
There is a sickness inside us.
就像胆汁窜升喉头的苦涩味
Rising like the bile that leaves that bitter taste at the back of our throats.
正坐在桌旁的每个人都一样
It's there in every one of you seated around the table.
我们否认病态存在
We deny its existence
直到有一天 身体背叛心灵
until one day the body rebels against the mind...
大声呼喊着 我生病了
and screams out, "I am not a well man."
你当然一心只想着并购的事
No doubt you will think only of the merger.
两个同等病态公司的龊龊结合
That unclean melding of two equally diseased institutions.
但事实不容忽视
But the truth cannot be ignored.
唯有了解病痛的根源
For only when we know what ails us
才有希望找到疗法
can we hope to find the cure.
我不会回来了
I will not return.
别再试图跟我联络
Do not attempt to contact me again.
罗兰·潘柏 敬笔
Sincerely, Roland E. Pembroke.
拉克哈先生
Well, Mr. Lockhart...
你怎么看这封信
what do you make of that?
他显然是疯了
Clearly, he's lost his mind.
跟我们想的一模一样
Our thoughts exactly.
他去参加两周水疗度假后
Man goes for a two-week spa vacation,
就完全精神崩溃了
and has a complete mental breakdown.
二十一世纪哪有人还在玩水疗这套
Who the hell takes the waters in the 21 st century anyway?
我想你了解信中有些内客不得外泄
I trust you understand the sensitivity of some of the information in that letter.
所以这是真的
So it's true.
这类并购会让我们成为
A merger of this kind will make us...
东海岸规模最大的金融服务公司
one of the biggest financial service firms on the Eastern Seaboard.
会议室的每个人都会赚很大
Something that stands to enrich everyone in this room.
包括你在内
Including you.
你的风评不错
We hear good things.
能处理好雷诺斯的帐户令人惊讨
Your work on the Reynolds account was inspired.
证交委员会肯定会想查公司帐簿
Of course, the SEC will want unfettered access to our books.
不法的地方一定会曝光
Any irregularities are sure to come out.
你该不会以为我们不会发现吧
You didn't really think we wouldn't find out?
我不晓得你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你以为你变得出新把戏吗
You think there's a trick you can pull we haven't tried?
年度绩效报告
这手法也太粗糙了
This is amateur.
拉克哈先生 能请教一件事吗
Can I ask you something, Mr. Lockhart?
你被三十公分的黑屌插过屁眼吗
You ever have a 12-inch black dick in your ass?
拉克哈先生 牢狱之灾
Prison, Mr. Lockhart.
你麻烦大了
You're in a lot of trouble.
若是这样 你早就把我交给警方了
If that were the case, you would have already turned me in.
所以我猜证交会要抓的是更高层的人
So, my guess is the SEC is after someone a little more senior.
可能是董事会的一员
Someone on the board, perhaps.
或精神状况明显不稳定的人
Or someone who's clearly unstable.
我们要你去瑞士带潘柏先生回来
We'd like you to go to Switzerland and bring Mr. Pembroke back to us.
是这样的
You see...
没有潘柏签名 并购案就不能完成
the merger cannot go through without Mr. Pembroke signing off...
有特定法律问题要处理
on certain legal matters.
我跟潘柏光生的关系不如莫里斯
I don't have the relationship with Mr. Pembroke that Morris had.
莫里斯去死
Fuck Morris.
莫里斯是好业务 可靠的顾家男人
Now, Morris was a good salesman, dependable family man.
愿他的灵魂安息
God rest his soul.
可是他没有远见
But he didn't have vision.
总得有人负起责任
Someone has to take responsibility.
贾许 又是我
Josh, it's me again.
一个半小时后 日经就结束交易了
In an hour and a half, the Nikkei closes.
你到时将拜恩的股票脱手
When it does, I want you to empty Banyon
买下葛兰柯的卖权
and buy puts in Glenco.
我现在传细节给你 快回我电话
I'm sending the details over now. And fucking call me back.
我不喜欢留言
I don't like leaving messages like this.
你是来治疗的吗
You're here for the cure?
不是 我只是探访
No, I'm just visiting.
你不介意吧
You mind?
你抽吧
Go ahead.
你比我大部分载的客人年轻
You're younger than most of my passengers.
你常替疗养院载客吗
Do a lot of driving for the sanitarium?
全部是我载的
All the driving.
我每星期都去车站接有钱人
Every week, I pick up rich people from the train...
载他们上山
and take them up the mountain.
只带有钱人吗
Only rich people, huh?
这里一定很贵
Must be expensive.
有钱人有富裕的问题
Well, wealthy people have wealthy problems.
我呢 过着简单的生活就满足了
Me, I'm happy with a simple life.
就这样 你都没有抱负
That's it? No ambition?
光是载人上下山就满足了
Just drive people up and down the mountain?
大部分的人会留下来
Most people tend to stay.
为什么
Why's that?
我想他们喜欢疗养院
I guess they like it there.
靠
Oh, shit.
电池剩余量0%
我不来水疗这一套
I don't go in for spas and that kind of thing.
我工作谋生 就跟我爸一样
I work for a living, like my father before me.
儿子会向父亲学习如何当男人吧
A son learns what it is to be a man from his father. Am I right?
这我就不知道了
I wouldn't know.
我没有父亲陪伴长大
I didn't grow up with my father.
你要去多久
How long will you be gone?
几天而已 洽公
Just a few days. It's business.
你的气色很差
You don't look well.
我没事 只是最近睡眠不足
I'm fine. I just haven't been sleeping much.
你需要休息
You need to rest.
我老是告诉你爸要休息
You know, I always told your father to rest...
但他就是不听
but he wouldn't listen.
他太没用了
He was weak.
你又不认识他
You didn't know him.
那是谁的错
And whose fault is that?
你在这轻还开心吗
So, are you happy here?
院方有好好照顾你吗
Are they taking good care of you?
人是来这里等死的 我哪会开心
People come here to die. Why would I be happy?
我要升官了
I'm getting a promotion.
我回来就能帮你换个好环境
So, when I get back I'll be able to move you to somewhere better.
靠近海滩什么
Somewhere near the beach or something.
你不会回来的
You won't come back.
我当然会
Of course I will.
又做新的芭蕾舞伶
Another ballerina?
她跟别的不一样
She's not like the others.
怎么说
Why's that?
她生活在梦境里
She lives in a dream.
可是她在跳舞
But she's dancing.
那是因为她不知道自己在作梦
That's because she doesn't know she's dreaming.
好友善的一群人
Friendly bunch.
对啊
Yeah.
村民跟山上的人一向不和
There's always been bad blood between the villagers and the people on the hill.
为什么
Why's that?
旧恨
History.
这个地方历史多久了
How old is this place?
地基可回溯到男爵时代
Foundations date back to the time of the barons.
几百年来 这块土地跟这里的人
For centuries, all this land and everyone in it...
都属于一个家族
belonged to one family.
范海克莫
The Von Reichmerls.
他们怎么了
What happened to them?
故事很曲折
Hmm. Interesting story.
最后一任男爵对血脉纯净着了魔
Apparently, the last baron was so obsessed with the purity of his bloodline...
他决定只有亲妹才能替他生子
he decided only his sister was clean enough to carry his child.
教会禁止他们结合后 他弃绝了上帝
When the church forbade the union, he renounced God.
下场一定很惨
That must have gone over well.
那还用说
No shit.
在他的新婚之夜
So on his wedding night...
村民上山
the villagers came up the hill...
追着男爵跟新娘进了地下墓穴
chased the Baron and his bride into the catacombs...
让他眼睁睁看着她被烧死
and made him watch while they burned her alive.
接着他们放火烧了这里 夷为平地
Then they burned the whole place to the ground.
好可怕的故事
That's a hell of a story.
对啊
Yeah.
但那是两百年前的事
But that was 200 years ago.
现在情况不一样了
A lot's changed since then.
我最多待二十分钟就出来
20 minutes max.
不急
No hurry.
欢迎
Welcome!
请问有什么事
May I help you?
我来找一个客人 罗兰·潘柏先生
I'm here to see a guest. Mr. Roland Pembroke.
抱歉 今天的探访时间已经过了
I'm sorry, but visiting hours are over for the day.
探访时间
上午11点－下午3点
我长途跋涉
I've come a long way.
可以破个例吗
Maybe you could make an exception.
不能破例
There are no exceptions.
我可以找经理谈吗
Is there a manager I could speak to?
在这里签名
Sign here.
麻烦你
Please.
谢谢 拉克哈先生
Thank you, Mr. Lockhart.
我尽量帮你处理
I'll see what I can do.
这里没有讯号
You won't get any service here.
这是疗程的一部分
Part of the treatment.
久了就习惯了
You get used to it.
“特赦”十个字母的写法是啥
What's a ten-letter word for amnesty?
不晓得
No idea.
免除
Exemption.
不对 那才九个字母
Nope. That's only nine.
赦免
Absolution.
对
Yes!
你喜欢玩字谜吗
You like puzzles?
不喜欢
Not really.
麻烦一下好吗
You mind?
谢谢
Thank you.
我想柜台的护士解释过了
I believe the reception nurse explained...
探访时问到三点整结束
that visiting hours end at 3:00 p.m. precisely.
她是说了 但我想你很清楚
She did. But as I'm sure you're aware...
潘柏依旧是某者要金融机构的总栽
Mr. Pembroke remains the CEO of a major financial institution.
在这种情况下 我希望你能开个
Under the circumstances, I was hoping you can make an...
特例
exception.
维他命
Vitamins.
如果我们要帮助来这疗养的人
If we are to help the people that come here...
就得维持体力
we must keep up our strength.
能请教是哪方面的事吗
May one ask what it is concerning?
商业机密
It's a business matter.
我无法多说
I'm not at liberty to say any more than that.
没间题 我希望你能了解
Of course. And I hope you understand
这里也有自己的规定
that we also have our rules.
我们的疗程想发挥最大的效果
Our treatments here are most effective...
就得严格限制接触现代世界的压力
when exposure to the stresses of the modern world is strictly limited.
沃莫主任对这点颇为坚持
Director Volmer is quite firm on that.
纯净健康
亨利·沃莫
- 水疗 - 是的
- Hydrotherapy? - That is correct.
就为了水 这路途还真远
That's a long way to come just for water.
本辽阳院建于古老的含水土层之上
The sanitarium is built over an ancient aquifer...
富有独特的活化特质
that offers uniquely rejuvenating qualities.
重建
Rebuilt.
在失火以后
After the fire.
是的
Yes.
历史充满黑暗面
History is full of darkness.
如果你想留张字条
If you would like to leave a note...
我会转交给潘柏先生
I'd happily pass it along to Mr. Pembroke.
彼得森先生
Mr. Pieterson?
我知道你在这里的工作很重要
I understand the work you do here is important...
你显然也是大忙人
and you're obviously a very busy man.
但如果你愿意在管理水上有氧运动 与按摩浴缸之余找时间
But if you wouldn't mind finding time between administering aqua aerobics and Jacuzzis...
通知潘柏先生有访客
to inform Mr. Pembroke he has a visitor...
有紧急要事找他
with information of the utmost urgency to him personally...
我会很感谢
I'd be grateful.
另一方面 如果你要我写字条
On the other hand, if you want me to write a note...
好随同早餐托盘塞进门底下
so you can slip it under his door with his breakfast tray...
他在早上按摩前却不见得能发现
on the off-chance he notices it before his morning rubdown...
那我恐怕不能接受
I'm afraid that's not gonna cut it.
我跑了六千多公里才到了这里
You see, I just traveled 4,000 miles to get here.
今晚有班红眼班机回纽约
There's a red-eye going back to New York tonight...
我会带潘柏先生飞回去
and I intend Mr. Pembroke and I to be on it.
你打算带潘柏先生跟你回纽约
You plan to take Mr. Pembroke back to New York with you?
有问题吗
Is that a problem?
这当然完全要看潘柏先生的意思
Of course, it is entirely up to Mr. Pembroke.
他是病患 不是囚犯
He's a patient, not a prisoner.
他的疗程到七点结束
He'll be in treatment until after 7:00.
你到时候来 我一定让你见他
If you'd like to come back then, I'll make sure he's available.
谢谢你的谅解
Thank you for your understanding.
你这么快离开
Leaving already?
- 好帅气的年轻人 - 你的朋友呢
- What a nice-looking young man. - Where's your friend?
到苏黎世最末班火车几点
What time's the last train to Zurich?
十点
Not till 10:00.
带我找间旅馆 我得打个电话
Get me to a hotel. I gotta make a call.
正妹
Pretty girl.
搞什么
What the fuck!
你要去多久
How long will you be gone?
几天而已
Just a few days.
你有在等人吗
Are we waiting for someone else?
没有人了
There is no one else.
睡得好吗
Sleep well?
- 我印象中没睡得这么甜过 - 山上的空气很新鲜
- I can't remember having slept better. - It's the mountain air.
拉克哈先生
Mr. Lockhart...
我是亨利沃莫 疗养院的主任
my name is Henrich Volmer. I am the director of the sanitarium here.
我在这里待多久了
How long have I been here?
三天
Three days.
老天
Oh, Jesus!
你的运气很好 骨折没粉碎
You can count yourself lucky. It was a clean break.
不过我觉得我有部分的责任
Although I do feel partly responsible.
居民说我应该射杀这里的鹿
The locals tell me I should hunt the deer on the property...
但我没办法伤害这些无辜的动物
but I can't bring myself to harm the innocent creatures.
毕竟 它们早就在这里了
After all, they were here long before us.
我得打电话到纽约
I need to call New York.
我迳行通知贵公司你出车祸的事了 如果你担心的是这个
I took the liberty of informing your office of the accident, if that's your concern.
他们跟我的意见一致
They agreed with me...
生意可以等 但你的健康不能等
that business can wait and your health cannot.
汉克葛林亲口说的
Hank Green said that?
就连华尔街大金融公司的代理总栽
Even the acting head of a major Wall Street finance firm...
对严重车祸的后果也无法争辩
can't argue with the consequences of a serious car accident.
这里的访客不多
We don't get many visitors here.
多数病患都有过丰功伟业
Most of my patients have done extraordinary things.
创造大笔财富
Built vast fortunes...
管理伟大的企业
commanded great empires...
却付出惨痛代价
but at a terrible cost.
他们没有人照顾
They have no one who cares for them.
潘柏先生运气很好
Mr. Pembroke is lucky.
他还有你
He has you.
所以你尽管休息吧
So, do your best to relax.
开心享受
Enjoy yourself.
这里是瑞士阿尔卑斯山脚
You are at the foot of the Swiss Alps...
世上最美的仙境之一 你就当作是强制放假吧
one of the most beautiful places in the world. Think of it as an enforced vacation.
但你们美国人不懂得放假的情趣吧
Although I know you Americans are not so good at vacations, are you?
别忘了 这是山上
And remember, you're at altitude.
适应可能要一段时间
It can take a while to acclimatize...
所以务必要多喝水
so please make sure you drink plenty of water.
相信我 我们会好好照顾你
Believe me, you're in good hands.
你迷路了吗
Are you lost?
对
Uh... Yeah.
我想是
I guess so.
你要去那里
Where is it you're supposed to be?
我不知道
I don't know.
你的名字
Name?
潘柏
Pembroke.
罗兰·潘柏
Roland Pembroke.
找到了
Here it is.
潘柏 六〇九房 蒸汽浴
Pembroke. Room 609. Steam bath.
对喔
Of course.
潘柏先生
Mr. Pembroke...
蒸汽浴要往那边走
the steam baths are in that direction.
你不能进去
You can't go in there.
要换衣服才行
Not like that.
潘柏
Pembroke?
您是潘柏先生吧
It is Mr. Pembroke, isn't it?
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
我是拉克哈 葛林先生派我来的
My name is Lockhart. Mr. Green sent me.
我还以为他们会叫莫里斯来
I thought they'd send Morris.
莫里斯死了
Morris is dead.
心脏病发
Heart attack.
潘柏先生 我是来带你回纽约的
Mr. Pembroke, I've come to bring you back to New York.
你要我离开这里
You want me to leave here?
几天就好
Just for a few days.
我恐怕办不到
I'm afraid I can't do that.
为什么不行
Why not?
我生病了
I'm not well.
你看起来好好的啊
You look all right to me.
那是因为你视而不见
That's because you are blind.
我从前也这样
As I was.
但你很快就会明白了
But soon you'll see.
放心吧 这里的人会好好照顾你
Rest assured, they'll take good care of you here.
我不是病人
I'm not a patient.
你的腿怎么了
What happened to your leg?
潘柏先生 纽约的情势很严峻
Mr. Pembroke, the situation in New York is really quite serious.
已经跟我与关了
No longer my concern.
主任要我别挂念事业
The director says I must not involve myself in business matters.
你见过沃莫主任了吗
Have you met Director Volmer?
今天早上见了
This morning.
他是很好的人
He is a great man.
心地善良 跟其他医生不一样
Kind man. Not like other doctors.
潘柏先生
Mr. Pembroke...
大家对血液走火入魔
This obsession with blood.
他们全搞错了
You see, they have it all wrong.
你知道身体有百分之六十五是水吗
Do you know the body is 65% water?
我们的体液必须净化
It's our fluids that must be purified.
并购有问题的消息走漏了
Word that the merger is in trouble has leaked.
股价因此暴跌 拉克哈
The share price is in free fall. Lockhart?
你该不会跟亨利拉克哈有关系吧
You're not any relation to Henry Lockhart, are you?
他是我爸
My father.
你认识他
You knew him?
我们在同时期创业
We started out together.
他的下场可真凄惨
Terrible, what happened to him.
听说有个男孩被留在车上
They said there was a boy left in the car.
说真的 我不太记得了
I don't remember much, to be honest.
他不应该受到我们那样的对待
He didn't deserve what we did to him.
- 什么意思 - 他是正直的人
- What do you mean? - He was an honest man.
我们却把他害惨了
And we destroyed him for it.
每天都有人被弄
Well, people get fucked over every day.
就看你有没有生存的本事
Either you have what it takes to survive, or you don't.
那我想你有咯
And I suppose you do.
这是你大老远跑来的原因
Is that why you came all this way?
为了抱负
Ambition?
那你就比我们都还要严重
Then you have it worse than any of us.
什么东西
What's that?
病啊
The sickness.
你爸早在我们之前就看清真相
Your father saw the truth long before the rest of us.
这些努力毫无意义
The pointlessness of the entire endeavor.
大家都做过可怕的事
We've all done terrible things.
可怕的事做太多了
So many terrible things.
交易金额是多少
What's it trading at?
什么
What?
股票的交易金额是多少
The stock! What's it trading at?
- 星期五收盘时每股八块五 - 寄生虫
- Eight and a half at close on Friday. - Parasites.
现在价格会更低
It'll be lower by now.
潘柏先生 大家都很关心你的健康
We're all concerned for your well-being, Mr. Pembroke.
几天就好
Just a few days.
部分帐户出现异常
There are certain irregularities in some of the accounts...
厘清后才能完成并购
that need to be clarified before the merger can be completed.
我想总得有人负起责任
And I suppose someone has to take responsibility.
之类的
Something like that.
那我最好去收拾东西
Then I better get my things.
我需要一辆车载我去车站
I need a car to take me to the station.
- 你能帮我叫车吗 - 我会尽量帮你处理
- Will you call one for me, please? - I'll see what I can do.
这是男爵吊死神父的地方
That's where the baron hung the priest.
- 什么 - 你看
- What's that? - See?
教堂原本在那里
The church would have been right over there...
现在被这怪建筑取代了 我确定
where that funny little building is now. I'm sure of it.
从前的人会远道而来
People used to come from miles around...
求圣水的神奇功效
for the miracles attributed to the holy water.
我想有些事情是不会变的
Guess some things don't change.
真是了不起
How marvelous.
不过这种暴力实在可怕
Terrible thing, though. Such violence.
娶妹妹就会这样
That's what you get for marrying your sister.
- 妹妹 - 对 一切都为了血统纯净吧
- Sister? - Yeah, it was all about a pure bloodline, wasn't it?
好精彩
How fascinating!
我一定要查一查
I must look into that.
很高兴你能走路了
Glad to see you're back on your feet!
我们听说车祸的事了
We heard about the accident.
- 你是美国人吧 先生贵姓 - 拉克哈
- You're American, aren't you, Mister... - Lockhart.
法兰克希尔 斯德哥尔摩人
Frank Hill. Stockholm.
这是伦敦来的奈尔先生
And this is Mr. Nair from London.
我原本住在孟买
Bombay, originally.
- 你见到业余历史学者瓦金斯太太了 - 没错 他真没礼貌
- I see you've met Mrs. Watkins, our amateur historian. - Yes, of course. How rude.
- 维多莉亚瓦金斯 我在全录待了四十年 - 你拉张椅子坐吧
- Victoria Watkins. 40 years at Xerox. - Why don't you pull up a chair?
我们三缺一
We need a fourth.
小心 他像波罗门的人一样会作弊
Careful. Like most Brahmins, he cheats.
从创投家的口中说出这句话
Coming from a venture capitalist,
我当是恭维
I take that as a compliment.
其实 我准备跟潘柏先生一起回纽约
Actually, I was just on my way back to New York with Mr. Pembroke.
那么他
Then he's...
他的身体好点了
He's feeling better?
够好了
Well enough.
我想这是好消息
I suppose that's wonderful news.
奈尔先生 可不是吗
Isn't that right, Mr. Nair?
很好的消息
Wonderful news.
瓦金斯太太
Mrs. Watkins...
你该做疗程了
time for your treatment.
没问题
Yes, of course.
拉克哈先生 很高兴认识你
Pleasure to meet you, Mr. Lockhart.
一路平安
Safe travels.
水里有东西吗
Something in the water?
在水底
At the bottom.
我什么都看不到
I don't see anything.
会痛吗
Did it hurt?
我不记得了
Can't remember.
这样反而好
Better that way.
我有看到你
I saw you.
之前看到过
Before.
你是这里的病人吗
Are you a patient here?
你比其他人都年轻很多
It's just, you're so much younger than everyone else.
沃莫主任说我是特殊案例
Director Volmer says I'm a special case.
那你呢
What about you?
你是来接受治疗的吗
Are you here for the cure?
不是
No.
其实我正要离开
Actually, I was just leaving.
没人离开过这里
No one ever leaves.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
为什么有人会想要离开
Why would anyone want to?
我懂你的意思
Yeah, I see your point.
你来的目的达到了吗
Did you get what you came for?
我来带一个人回纽约
Well, I came to bring someone back to New York.
所以我的目的达到了
So, yeah. I did.
他想走吗
Does he want to go?
不太想
Not really.
你刚刚哼唱那首歌
That song you were singing.
是在哪里学的
Where did you learn that?
我得走了
I have to go now.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
汉娜
Hannah.
今日探访时间已过
潘柏先生
Mr. Pembroke?
潘柏呢
Where's Pembroke?
原本在这间病房的人去哪了
The patient that was in this room, where is he?
我还以为你是潘柏
I thought you were Pembroke.
大家知道从前胃痛的建议疗法吗
Do you know what they used to recommend for the common stomach ailment?
使用水蛭
The application of leeches.
根据诊断 我一向同情水蛭
Based on the diagnosis, I always pitied the leech.
拉克哈先生
Mmm. Mr. Lockhart...
请加入我们吧
please, won't you join us?
鲟鱼很好吃 你爱鹿肉也行
The sturgeon is excellent, unless of course you prefer the venison.
我不能浪费那头鹿
I couldn't let it go to waste.
潘柏呢
Where's Pembroke?
很不幸 潘柏先生病情加重了
Mr. Pembroke has unfortunately taken a turn for the worse.
恐怕你们谈生意的事
I fear your conversation about business matters...
让他的情况恶化了
has set him back somewhat.
但不重要
But, no matter. We have moved him on
我们送他去做下一阶段的疗程了
to the next stage of treatment.
我觉得他看来好好的
He looked all right to me.
但你不是医生
But you're not a doctor.
说不定该征求第二意见了
Maybe it's time for a second opinion.
要走要留就看潘柏先生的意思
That, of course, is up to Mr. Pembroke.
但他不能见客
And he's not available.
自从我来了以后
Ever since I got here...
你们就一跟我兜圈子
you people have been giving me the runaround.
请你降低音量
I would ask you please to keep your voice down.
我们可不想让客户不开心吧
We wouldn't wanna upset the clientele, would we?
拉克哈先生
Mr. Lockhart, giving you the runaround
我并没有跟你兜圈子
is the furthest thing from my mind.
我只关心我病患的福利
My sole concern is for the welfare of my patients.
病人开始好转就会影响你们的生意
It's bad for business if people start getting better.
我说得对吗
Am I right?
拉克哈先生 你的言下之意是什么
What are you implying, Mr. Lockhart?
老人花大钱做什么 喝水
Old people paying through the teeth for what? Water?
你的开销到底是多少
What's your overhead anyway?
那不关你的事
That is not your concern.
我不想把律师牵扯进来
I don't wanna have to get lawyers involved...
但我是来带潘柏回纽约的
but I came to get Pembroke back to New York...
我要把人带走 就算我得敲破他的头
and that's what I'm gonna do, if I have to hit him over his head...
揪着头发把他抱出去也在所不辞
and drag him out by his hair.
拉克哈先生 你还好吗 你的脸色很苍白
Are you feeling all right, Mr. Lockhart? You seem pale.
我没事
I'm fine.
你流血了
You're bleeding.
什么
What?
你还是坐下来吧
Perhaps you should sit down.
没有脑震荡迹拿
No signs of concussion.
你会头痛 出现幻觉吗
Any headaches, hallucinations?
没有
No.
你可以穿衣服了
You may dress.
你有在喝水吗
Are you drinking the water?
有
Yes.
很好
Good.
一定要喝水
Make sure you do.
我在车祸后擅自替你做了几项检查
I took the liberty of running a few tests after the accident.
汉娜
Hannah.
这是她吧
Isn't it?
对
Yes.
她是特殊案例
She's a very special case.
什么意思
What does that mean exactly?
她小时候遭遇严重的创伤
She was exposed to serious trauma when she was very young.
她的发育迟缓
Her development was delayed.
直到十一岁才开口说话
Hannah did not utter a word until she was 11 years old.
请你要了解
Please understand...
拉克哈先生
Mr. Lockhart...
她对我来说 情同女儿
she is like a daughter to me.
但我们要讨论的是你的事
But we're here to discuss you.
你的体液不平衡
An imbalance in your fluids.
重大器官损伤
Strain to the major organs.
免疫系统耗竭
Depleted immune system.
许多迹象指出你跟多数病患一样
Many indicators that you have in common with most of my patients...
但我坦承从来没看过
but I will confess I have never seen a case...
这么严重的病情
as advanced as this...
发生在这么年轻的人身上
in someone so young.
是吗
Is that right?
拉克哈先生 告诉我
Tell me, Mr. Lockhart...
你最后一次觉得身强体壮是何时
when was the last time that you actually felt well?
在你来之前
Before you came here, when was the last time...
你最后一次一觉到天亮是何时
that you even slept through the night?
心理可能会说谎
The mind may lie...
但身体可骗不了人
but the body cannot.
我想帮助你
I should like to help you.
本院提供的是
What we offer here...
简单的净化过程
is a simple process of purification.
远离现代世界的压力
Away from pressures of the modern world.
回归单纯的年代
A return to a simpler time.
潘柏先生一两天内不能出远门
Mr. Pembroke will not be ready to travel for a day or two.
你愿意的话
And if you're willing...
我想推荐一个疗程
I would like to recommend a treatment.
我能跟当班的护士说
I can speak to the duty nurse...
今天晚上就能开始进行
and we may be able to start as early as this evening.
你觉得有必要就做吧
If you think it's necessary.
很好
Good.
葛瑞塔
Greta?
罗兰·潘柏
拉克哈先生 你的运气真好
You're in luck, Mr. Lockhart.
我们能马上帮你安排
We can get you in right away.
“VR”
"VR."
范海克莫的意思
Von Reichmerl.
这是重建时发现的
It was found during the reconstruction.
那这就是男爵的坠子咯
Then it belong to the baron?
其实是男爵夫人的
The baroness, actually.
凡妮莎范海克莫
Vanessa Von Reichmerl.
她体弱多病
She was sickly.
男爵执意要找到疗法
The Baron was obsessed with finding a cure.
事实上 他是第一个
It was he, in fact, who first discovered
发现这里的水有疗效
the medicinal properties of our water.
他无所不用其极
He sacrificed everything.
他一定很爱她
He must have loved her very much.
是的
Yes.
当妹妹一样爱
Like a sister.
历史以道德角度批判他当然是对的
History is right, of course, to judge him on moral grounds.
但身为科学之人
But, as a man of science...
我对他只有欣赏
I can't help but admire him.
当班护士会带你去隔离区
The duty nurse will escort you to our isolation wing.
谢谢
Thank you.
拉克哈先生
Mr. Lockhart...
希望你不会介意
If you wouldn't mind.
这样我们才能监控你的进展
Just so we can keep an eye on your progress.
维多莉亚·瓦金斯
拉克哈先生 您准备好了吗
Are you ready, Mr. Lockhart?
那我们开始吧
Then let us begin.
地球的生物首先从水中出现
Life on this planet first came from water.
我们头九个月沉浸在液体中
We spend the first nine months of our existence submerged...
身体多数为液体所组成
our bodies mostly liquid.
感官去除室能模拟
This sensory deprivation chamber simulates a return...
让人回归胚胎状态
to that embryonic state.
就当成是净化心灵
Think of it as a cleansing of the mind...
与净化身体吧
as much as the body.
有些病患会心跳加速
Some patients experience increased heart rate...
出现幻觉
visions...
甚至出现早期记忆
even primal memories.
但请放 这只是毒素排出体外
But rest assured, it's just the toxins leaving the system.
完全投入这个过程
Give yourself over completely to the process...
你就会看到成果
and you will see the results.
注意看好他
Keep a close eye on him.
好的
Yes, sir.
拉克哈先生 疗程总共三十分钟
Mr. Lockhart... the treatment lasts 30 minutes.
我会从这里监控 有任何问题
I'll be monitoring you from here. If you have any issues...
此敲水槽
just tap on the side of the tank.
退后
Get back!
过去五天 股市完全崩盘
In the last five days, a total collapse.
道琼指数狂跌超过五百零八点
The Dow plunging over 508 points...
华尔街弥漫着恐慌
as panic spread throughout Wall Street...
有超过三分之一的获利
wiping out more than one-third of the gains...
从这罕见的五年牛市蒸发
from this rare, five-year bull market.
其中超过一半发生于单一交易日
More than half of that in a single trading day.
纽约证交所主席约翰菲兰
Chairman of New York Stock Exchange, John Phelan...
试图安定投资人信心
tried to reassure investors.
爸
Dad?
Dad!
拉克哈先生 你没事吧
Mr. Lockhart, are you all right?
放开我
Get off me.
别激动
Try to stay calm.
很抱歉 仪器一定出了问题
I'm terribly sorry. Something must have gone wrong with the machine.
水里有东西
There's something in the water.
水里他妈的有东西
There's something in the fucking water.
拉克哈先生 水里没东西
There is nothing in the water, Mr. Lockhart.
可是我看到了
But I saw them.
主任解释过了
As the Director explained...
这套疗程会使某些病患出现幻觉
some patients experience visions with this particular treatment.
这只是毒素排出体外
Just the toxins leaving the body.
是疗程的一部分
It's all part of the cure.
你得休息了
You need to rest now.
我扶你回去房间
I will help you to your room.
逮到你了
Got you.
拉克哈 早
Morning, Lockhart.
你好点了吗
Feeling better?
要一起吃早餐吗
Joining us for breakfast?
鳕鱼咖哩饭很香
The kedgeree is excellent.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
你可得好好保持体力
You must keep up your strength.
瓦金斯太太
Mrs. Watkins?
教堂的原址
That building where the church used to be...
现在的用途是什么
What's it used for now?
我也不晓得
I couldn't say.
男爵跟他妹妹的事你说对了
You were right about the baron and his sister.
但那不是村民烧了这里的源因
But that's not the reason the villagers burned the place down.
而是实验的关系
It was on account of the experiments.
某种医学实验
Some sort of medical experiments.
男爵夫人 范海克莫 凡妮莎 实验 尸体 妹妹 神父 婚礼 大火
他用自己的人民当白老鼠
Apparently performed on his own peasants.
有些人失踪了
People went missing.
后来
And then...
在一八一四年
Im Jahre 1814...
农夫在耕田时发现死人
farmers, tilling their fields, stumbled on human bodies...
遭到破坏且皮包骨
disfigured and emaciated.
就像埃及木乃伊一样
Dried up like the mummies of Egypt.
他在找疗法
He was looking for a cure.
- 疗法 - 为了治疗男爵夫人
- A cure? - For the baroness.
她病了
She was sick.
我了解了
Oh, I see.
我就知道你喜欢字谜
I knew you liked puzzles.
治愈
果然没错
Of course.
瓦金斯太太
Mrs. Watkins...
你该做疗程了
time for your treatment.
你确定吗
Are you certain?
我早上才做过一次 我确定
I just had one this morning. I'm sure of it.
时间表上有你
I have you on the schedule.
我今天一定是有问题
I must not be feeling myself today.
这里黑暗又邪恶
There is a terrible darkness here.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
抱歉 我不懂
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
我看到你跟一个病人在一起
I thought I saw you with a patient.
不是 病人
No. Patient.
好
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
你要去游泳吗
Going for a swim?
我不能游
I'm not supposed to.
怎么说
Why's that?
因为我生病了
On the account of my condition.
我还以为水会让病情好转
Thought the water made you better.
跟你说过了 我是特殊案例
Told you. I'm a special case.
对
Right.
从这里到镇上有多远
How far is it to town?
我想有几公里吧
A few miles, I think.
你要一路走过去吗
Are you going to walk all the way?
除非你想借我脚踏车
Unless you wanna lend me your bike.
你要拿什么来谢我
What will you give me?
这原本是我妈的
It was my mother's.
她的眼睛闭着
Her eyes are closed.
对 她在作梦 只是她不知道
Yeah, she's dreaming. She just doesn't know it.
她醒过来会怎样
What happens if she wakes up?
我不知道
I don't know.
我妈一在没有说到结局
My mother never finished the story.
所以我们说定了吗
So, we got a deal?
你要怎么骑车
How will you ride it?
你可以一起来啊
Maybe you could come along.
我不能出去
I'm not supposed to.
你一向这么听话吗
You always do what you're supposed to do?
没关系
It's okay.
要来吗
Coming?
你要喝啤酒吗
Want a beer or something?
我不知道 我要吗
I don't know. Do I?
我不知道你想要什么
I don't know what you want.
好 你喝我就喝
All right. If you're having one.
你还在这里
Still here?
我以为你只走访客
Thought you were just visiting.
你看起来好多了
You've looked better.
你也是
Same to you.
你的车子还好吗
How's the car?
我的车全毁了
That car was a piece of shit.
疗养院赔的钱够我买一辆新车
Sanitarium offered me enough to buy a new one.
所以 谢天谢地
So, gracias a Dios.
事出必有因 对吗
Everything happens for a reason, right?
你喝太多了
You drink too much.
你可别开车
I hope you're not driving.
你们两个是从山上来的
You two are from up on the hill?
对
That's right.
这里不常有病人下来
We don't get many patients down here.
这些小孩心地善良
Good kids at heart.
只是没教好
Just weren't raised properly.
不尊重传统
No respect for tradition.
你知道镇上有医生吗
Know if there's a doctor in town?
医生全都在山上了
All the doctors are up on the hill.
有药师吗
A pharmacist?
之类的人
Something like that?
可以找彼特 绕过去就到了
There's Pieter. Over the road.
他是医生吗
He a doctor?
够接近了
Close enough.
你不喜欢
Don't you like it?
不喜欢
No.
怎么 这辈子没喝过啤酒
What, you never had a beer before?
你待在疗养院多久了
How long have you been at the sanitarium?
从我有记忆以来
Since I can remember.
那你的家人呢
What about your family?
我妈在我小时候被火烧死了
My mother died in a fire when I was young.
沃莫主任说等我好一点
Director Volmer says that my father will come for me
我爸就会来接我
when I'm better.
他会来看你吗
Does he visit?
等我好一点他就会来
He'll come when I'm better.
- 维他命 - 对
- Vitamins? - Mmm-hmm.
我可以试试吗
Can I try?
好
Okay.
味道像臭海鲜
Tastes like sweaty seafood.
你最后会习惯的
You get used to it. Eventually.
你在这里待一下没关系吧
Will you be okay here for a few minutes?
我得去处理一件事 不会太久
I just have to go see about something. But I won't be long.
好啊
Uh... Yeah. Okay.
哈罗
Hello?
你知道这里有医生吗
Do you know if there's a doctor here?
你画的是什么
What's that you're drawing?
他不会跟你说话的
He won't talk to you.
他不会说话
Doesn't know how.
那是城堡
That's the castle...
失火的时候
when they burned it down.
这是我孙子威莫许
My grandson, Wilmosh.
他喜欢鬼故事
He likes ghost stories.
你有什么事
What can I do for you?
你可以帮我看一下 这份病历上面写什么吗
Could you take a look at this, tell me what it says?
这是人的吗
Human?
对
That's right.
不是我的专业
Not my line.
我愿意付你钱
I'll pay you.
这样是多少钱
How much is this?
没多少
Not much.
但是够了
But enough.
你有棉条吗
Got a tampon?
我朋友的大姨妈来了
My friend's time of the month.
怪胎
Freak.
所以他能出远门吗
So is he fit to travel?
他生病了
He's not a well man.
有些是牙科的病历吧
Some of those are dental records, aren't they?
- 对 - 那是什么意思
- That's right. - What do they mean?
他在掉牙齿
His teeth are falling out.
可能的病因是什么
What could cause something like that?
撇开先前的病不说 我认为是
Barring any pre-existing condition, I'd say...
慢性脱水
chronic dehydration.
脱水
Dehydration?
山上的人都只会喝水而已啊
All they do up there is drink water.
我不是医生
I'm not a doctor.
抱歉 我还有事
Now, if you'll excuse me...
等一下
Wait a second.
男爵的实脸
The baron's experiments.
有人在田里发现尸体 对吗
They found bodies in the fields, right?
跟木乃伊一样
Dried up like mummies.
说不定事情有关联
Maybe there's some kind of connection.
两百年前 男爵在新婚之夜 就被活活烧死了
The baron was burned alive on his wedding night 200 years ago.
对 但这是现在的事
Yeah, but this is happening now.
人们会来这里治疗
People come here for the cure.
男爵就是要找疗法 他的夫人病了
That's what the baron was looking for. His wife was sick.
她没生病
She wasn't sick.
她是不能生育
She was infertile.
他们努力了很多年
They tried for years.
但男爵夫人都半途流产
But the baroness could not carry a child to term.
大家说她的身体
They say her body rejected the fetuses
因为胎儿畸形产生排斥
because they were deformed.
抱歉 我真的有事
Now, you must excuse me.
我得了结这头牛的痛苦
I have to put this animal out of its misery.
它怎么了
What's wrong with it?
他溜达到了不该去的地方
Wandered off where it wasn't supposed to be.
摔断了腿
Broke its leg.
就像你一样
Like you.
我发现它困在排水沟
Found it trapped in a drainage ditch...
喝臭沟水
drinking sewage water.
我得打一通长途电话
I need to make a phone call. Long distance.
信用卡拿来
Your credit card.
拉克哈
Lockhart.
葛林先生
Mr. Green.
你到底去哪了
Where the hell have you been?
我有一个问题
I have a question.
潘柏有任何旧疾吗
Did Pembroke have any pre-existing conditions?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
他来之前有生什么病吗
Before he got here. Any medical conditions? Was he sick?
没有 他是保健狂
No. The guy is a fucking health nut.
会喝甘蓝汁那种神经病
Drank kale for Christ's sake.
到底是怎么回事
Now what the fuck is going on?
你四天前就该回来的
You were supposed to be here four days ago.
对 可是后来我出意外了
Yeah. But there was an accident.
什么意外
What accident?
什么
What?
我不懂 他们说有打电话给你
I don't understand. They said they called you.
没人打给我
Nobody called.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
拉克哈 我得跟你重申
Lockhart, do I have to reiterate to you...
你出这趟差的重要性吗
the importance of what you've been sent there to do?
二十四小时内带潘柏上飞机
Get Pembroke on a plane within the next 24 hours...
否则这里就天下大乱了
or this whole place goes ass over tits.
连你也一样遭殃 懂吗
And you with it. Understand me?
拉克哈
Lockhart?
Lockhart!
- 我有话跟你说 - 喂
- I need to speak with you - Hey, hey, hey.
你说没人会离开这里是啥意思
You said no one ever leaves. What does that mean?
你弄痛我了
You're hurting me.
- 他们会怎样 - 拜托放开我
- What happens to them? - Please let me go.
院方为什么不让我见潘柏
Why won't they let me see Pembroke?
- 你知道内幕 对不对 - 不知道
- You know something, don't you? - No.
这是什么 你为什么是特殊案例
What is this stuff? What makes you special?
阿道失 滚开
Fuck off, Adolf!
嘿
Hey!
- 快点 - 不
- Come on. - No!
- 我付了钱跳这支舞 - 不
- I paid for this dance. - No!
放开她
Let her go!
跋脚的滚回疗养院吧
Go back to the sanitarium, cripple.
不
No!
不 拜托住手
No! Please, stop!
我不是病人
I am not a patient.
汉娜
Hannah.
她或许有女人的外表
She may look like a woman...
但她的内心只是个孩子
but she's just a child.
拉克哈先生 无知
Ignorance, Mr. Lockhart...
是科学的大敌
is the great enemy of science.
我要见潘柏
I wanna see Pembroke.
你会见到的
And you will.
拉克哈先生 你来不来
Coming, Mr. Lockhart?
什么事也没发生
Nothing happened.
那是因为我及时赶到
That's because I arrived when I did.
有拉克哈在
Lockhart was there.
他都被刀架住脖子了
With a knife to his throat.
汉娜
Hannah...
拉克哈连自己都照顾不了
Mr. Lockhart is not able to look after himself,
更何况是照顾你
let alone you.
他不像我可以保护你
He can't protect you the way I can.
- 我不需要保护 - 你当然需要
- I don't need protecting. - Of course you do.
我们只是出去玩
We were just having fun.
他跟别人不一样
He's not like the others.
他很年轻
He's young.
干吗
What?
- 怎么了 - 没事
- What is it? - Nothing.
- 让我看 - 不要
- Let me see. - No.
我是你的医生 过来
I'm your doctor. Come here.
不要 别碰我
No! Don't touch me!
我什么时候会做好准备
When will I be ready?
就快了
Soon.
什么时候
When?
要有耐心
Patience.
过来
Come here.
我叫你过来
I said, come here.
一直都是我照顾你的吧
Now, haven't I always looked after you?
你很快就会好转
Soon, I will make you better.
也会感谢我的
And you will thank me.
然后我爸就会来了
And my father will come?
对
Yes.
小宝贝 休息吧
Get some rest, my little lamb.
有事吗
Bitte?
我出问题了
I have a problem with my...
可以给我吗
May I?
我把它放进牛奶里吧
I'll just pop it in some milk, shall I?
潘柏 输液区
好了
There we are.
瓦金斯太太
Mrs. Watkins?
潘柏呢
Where's Pembroke?
你带他走了
You took him.
回纽约去了
Back to New York.
什么 没有
What? No.
院方把他移走了 他在下面这区
They moved him. He's down here somewhere.
记得你跟我说过实验的事吗
You told me about the experiments, remember?
你的字谜
Your puzzle?
我喜欢字谜
I like puzzles.
对
Yeah.
我留给你了
I left it for you.
你会明白的
You'll see.
听我说
Listen to me.
实验
The experiments...
我觉得又开始了
I think they're happening again.
男爵夫人无法生育
The baroness was infertile.
不是实验
Not experiments.
是疗法
A cure.
她在新婚之夜就怀孕了
She was pregnant the night of the wedding.
村民烧死她之前
Before they burned her...
把胎儿挖出来
the villagers cut out the fetus...
扔进含水土层里
and threw it in the aquifer.
那孩子没死
The child survived.
她不晓得
She doesn't know.
抱歉 我不懂
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
别激动
Take it easy.
马可斯
Marcus!
没事
It's all right.
拉克哈先生
Mr. Lockhart...
不管我走到哪里
every time I turn around,
你总是在不该去的地方
you're somewhere you're not supposed to be.
我想我迷路了
I guess I'm lost.
我只是在找路回房间
I'm just trying to find my way back to my room.
这个楼层禁止进入 到处都有标示
This is a restricted floor. There are signs everywhere.
你不是不小心撞进来的吧
Surely you didn't just wander down here by accident?
你到底在找什么
What is it exactly that you are looking for?
我的牙齿有问题
I had a problem with my tooth.
你的牙齿
Your tooth?
其实 我感觉好多了
Actually, it's feeling much better.
麻烦你告诉我怎么回房间
If you could just point me in the direction of my room.
别胡说
Nonsense.
我们可不能让你感染了
We can't let you get an infection.
你一定要让我们照顾你
You must let us take care of you.
毕竟
After all...
这是你来疗养院的原因
that's why you're here.
病人的牙齿健康都由布南医生负责
Doctor Brennan takes care of all our patients' dental needs.
对不起
I'm sorry.
汉娜的事是我不对
Hmm? About Hannah.
不会有下次了
It won't happen again.
告诉我
Tell me...
你去镇上做什么
what were you doing in town?
只是喝啤酒
Just having a beer.
你们要干吗
What are you doing?
放开我
Get your hands off me!
拉克哈先生 这是为了你的安全着想
It's all for your own safety, Mr. Lockhart.
本院不相信化学麻醉
We don't believe in chemical anesthesia at the institute.
它的杂质会抑制疗效
The impurities inhibit the cure.
但你会发现只要焦点对了
But, you will find that with a proper focus...
心理就能克服所有的痛苦
the mind can overcome any amount of pain.
拉克哈先生 怀抱信任吧
Trust, Mr. Lockhart. Hmm?
如果我们不能彼此信任
I mean, if we can't trust each other...
我又怎么帮得了你呢
then how can I help you?
阿伯莫太太
Mrs. Abramov...
很高兴你来了
so glad that you are here.
你要在这里待多久
How long do we have you with us?
就两个星期
Just two weeks.
我可能带太多行李了
I probably overpacked.
没有的事
Nonsense.
在本院时间之飞快会让你惊讶的
You'll be surprised how time just slips away here at the institute.
快开车
Drive!
- 你的脸怎么了 - 开车就对了
- What happened to your face? - Just drive!
他们压住我 硬拔表的牙齿
They held me down and pulled my tooth out.
他们威胁我
They threatened me.
他们为什么要这么做
Why would they do that?
因为我知道他们的勾当
Because I know what they've done.
有个房间全部都是尸体 像标本一样在水缸里漂浮
There is a room full of bodies floating in tanks like specimens.
这可是非常严重的指控
These are very serious allegations.
没错
No shit.
沃莫医师受人尊敬
Director Volmer is a well-respected man.
疗养院对地方经济举足轻重
The sanatorium is of great importance for the local economy.
载我上去 我带你去看
Take me up there, and I'll show you what I saw.
你身上有带证件吗
Do you have any identification on you?
没有 都被他扪扣走了
No, they have everything.
那么我可以跟谁谈话
Well, then, is there someone I could speak to...
证实你的身分 你有家人吗
who might confirm you are who you say you are? Family?
希望你能谅解查证你身分的必要性
I hope you understand the need to verify your identity.
你可以打到我的办公室
You can call my office.
好
All right.
你要喝咖啡或茶吗
Can I get you coffee or tea?
你有酒吗
You got anything stronger?
当然有
Of course.
放心吧
Rest assured...
我们会查个水落石出
we will get to the bottom of this.
谢谢
Thank you.
拉克哈先生 我们一直在担心你
Mr. Lockhart, we've been worried about you.
不要过来
Stay away from me!
他是你们的病人吗
Is this man a patient of yours?
没错
Yes, that's right.
我不是病人 我是出了意外
I'm not a patient. I was in an accident.
你签了住院表了 我有带来
You signed the admission form. I have it right here.
狗屁
That's bullshit.
记得我警告过你可能会出现幻觉吧
I did warn you about possible delusions, remember?
那是毒素排出体外的副作用
A side effect of the toxins leaving the body.
那我的腿是幻觉吗
And my leg, is that a delusion?
拉克哈先生自从来了以后 就一直搞破坏
Mr. Lockhart has been a disruptive element since he arrived.
他偷走不对外公开的病历
He stole confidential medical files...
攻击一名牙科人员
assaulted a member of our Dental staff...
还威胁潘柏先生
and threatened Mr. Pembroke.
我没有威胁任何人
I didn't threaten anybody!
我想你的确切字句是
I believe your exact words were...
就算敲破他的头
"If I have to, I'll hit him over the head
揪着头发把他拖出去也在所不辞
"and drag him out by his hair."
我被派来就是要带潘柏回钮约
I was sent here to bring Pembroke back to New York!
根据你的雇主葛林先生的说词
According to your employer, a Mr. Green...
你遭到证交委员会调查
you're being investigated by the Securities and Exchange Commission.
你是他们的人
You're one of them.
拉克哈先生 听听你自己说的话
Listen to yourself, Mr. Lockhart.
你生病了
You're not a well man.
别再说我病了
Stop saying that!
- 让我们帮你吧 - 别过来
- Let us help you. - Get back!
我知道实验的事
I know about the experiments.
男爵跟他夫人的事
The baron and his wife.
他太常跟瓦金斯太太说话了
He has been spending time with Mrs. Watkins.
瓦金斯是谁
Who is Watkins?
她在来我们这之前住过精神病院
She was institutionalized before she came to us.
别人都会顺着她
The others humor her...
很显然的 拉克哈因为生病
but clearly Mr. Lockhart's condition
被她的除谋论影响了
has made him susceptible to her conspiracies.
我知道你们在玩什么把戏
I know what you're trying to do. All of you.
想让我以为我疯了
You're trying to make me think I'm insane.
我看过这种情况
I have seen this before.
这很常见
It's not uncommon.
深植内心的童年创伤浮出台面
Some deep-seated childhood trauma rises to the surface...
病患逃避一辈子就会这样
something a patient has been running from their entire life.
就你的情况来说
In your case...
我认为你因为你父亲的死
I would say misplaced guilt...
而怪罪自已
over the death of your father.
你怎么会知道这件事 我从来没跟你说过
How do you know about that? I never told you that.
你不用多说
You didn't have to.
这是你来本院的原因吧
That's why you came to us, isn't it?
我看到他了
I saw him.
潘柏死了
Pembroke is dead.
闹成这样就是为了这件事
That's what this is all about?
邪恶的医生杀死病人
The evil doctor killing off his patients?
没错
That's right.
好 那我们就请教潘柏先生吧
All right. Perhaps we should consult Mr. Pembroke.
你认识这个人吗
Do you know this man?
他想把我强押回去
He tried to take me back against my will.
潘柏先生
Pembroke?
拜托别让他靠近我
Please keep him away from me.
你死了
You were dead.
你想提告吗
Do you wish press charges?
没有必要
That won't be necessary.
拉克哈先生不是坏人
Mr. Lockhart is not a criminal.
他只是病了
He is a patient.
致董事会
To the members of the board...
各位派我来此有所目的
You sent me here for a purpose.
那就是强押一个人
To retrieve a man against his will...
带回你们的世界
and bring him back to your world.
但我现在明白了
But I realize now...
那不是我来的原因
that is not the reason I am here.
每个人的内在都有某种病态
There is a sickness inside each of us.
我们竭尽所能否认它的存在
We do our best to deny its existence...
用逃避
dealing in lies...
或是谎言来面对
and distraction.
直到有一天
Until one day the body rebels against the mind
身体对心理反抗呐喊
and screams out...
我生病了
"I am not a well man."
人无法忽视真相
A man cannot unsee the truth.
一旦看见光明
He cannot willingly return to darkness...
就不可能自愿回归黑晴或选择失明
or go blind once he has the gift of sight...
就如同他无法回到未出生时
any more than he can be unborn.
肏
Fuck.
汉娜
Hannah!
别过来
Stay away from me.
- 汉娜 - 别过来
- Hannah. - Stay away from me.
- 我们得走了 - 我叫你别过来
- We need to go. - I said stay away!
好了 没事了 请享用餐点吧
There. Everything is all right. Please enjoy your meal.
汉娜
Hannah?
你做了什么事
What have you done?
我怎么了
What's happening to me?
好了
Here, here, here.
没事 你安全了
It's all right. You're safe now.
别碰她
Leave her alone.
拉克哈先生 她已经被你弄得够烦了
Haven't you upset her enough, Mr. Lockhart?
请送病人回房
Please, escort the patient back to his room.
我不是他妈的病人
I am not a fucking patient!
来啊
Come on!
受够这里的跋脚跟老人了吗
Had enough of cripples and old people?
来找我试试看啊
Try it with me!
够了 拉克哈先生
That's enough! Mr. Lockhart...
我看得出你非常沮丧
I can see you're extremely upset.
你来我的办公室吧
Why don't you come with me to my office...
我们可以讨论你的疑惑
and we can discuss whatever's on your mind.
不要
No.
我们就在这里谈
We're gonna talk about it right here.
在所有人面前谈
In front of everybody.
我认为这样不太好
I don't think that's a good idea.
他在害大家生病
He's making you sick.
这个地方会害你生病
This place is making you sick!
病原在水里
It's in the water.
拉克哈先生
Mr. Lockhart.
我看到跟木乃伊一样的尸体
I saw the bodies dried up like mummies!
看看你们
Look at you people!
你们在掉牙齿
Your teeth are falling out!
你们快死了却不自觉
You're dying, and you can't even see it.
可是我是来治疗的
But I'm here for the cure.
根本没有疗法
There is no cure!
你们看不出来吗
Don't you see?
就是他害大家生病的
He's the one that is making you sick!
你们没有问题
There's nothing wrong with you people!
如果我是你 就不会这这么做
I wouldn't do that, if I were you.
你们没有问题
There's nothing wrong with you.
对
Yes.
Yes!
就是这样
That's it!
站起来吧
Stand up!
快点
Come on!
对
Yes!
站起来
Stand up!
他在害你们生病
He is making you sick!
对 这样就对了 来吧
Yes, that's it. Come on.
这样就对了
That's it!
你们没生病
There's nothing wrong with you!
- 我生病了 - 我生病了
- I am not well. - I am not well.
我生病了
I am not well.
你们要干吗
What are you doing?
他妈的放开我
Get the fuck off me!
不
No. No, no!
放开我
Get off me.
救救我 救我
Help me! Help!
潘柏
Pembroke.
潘柏先生
他们把你怎么了
What have they done to you?
把我怎么了
Done to me?
我从来没感觉这么好过
I've never felt better.
拉克哈先生 放轻松
Relax, Mr. Lockhart.
疗程很快就结束了
It'll all be over soon.
没错 了不起的生物
Ah, yes. Remarkable creatures.
在别的地方 这生物顶多才活十来年
Anywhere else on the planet, this species lives a dozen years, at most.
但在我们的含水土层里
Here, in our aquifer...
它们能活三百年
they can live 300.
就人类的生理而言
For the human physiology...
水对人来说挺毒的 你也发现了
the effect of the water can be quite toxic as you have discovered.
但经过适当的过滤就没问题了
Unless, of course, it is properly filtered.
这是男爵发明的疗程
The baron devised the process.
利用他土地所属的人民实脸
Using the bodies of peasants that belonged to his land...
他设法将水蒸馏至
he managed to distill the water...
活络生命的精髓
to its life-giving essence.
他当然为了他的聪明才智 付出惨痛代价
Of course, he paid a terrible price for his ingenuity.
他唯一的错
His only mistake...
就是利用了非自愿的人当对象
was to use subjects who were unwilling.
幸好 时代不一样了
Luckily, times have changed.
这两百年是人类史上 生产力最旺盛的时期
The last 200 years have been the most productive in human history.
世人摆脱上帝
Man rid himself of God...
摆脱阶级以及赋予人类意义的一切
of hierarchy, of everything that gave him meaning...
最后只剩下崇拜自我野心的空虚感
until he was left worshiping the empty altar of his own ambition.
这是他们来此的原因
That is why they come.
他们像你一样
Men like you.
拉克哈先生 你说得很对
You're quite right, Mr. Lockhart.
没有人离开过
No one ever leaves.
但你搞错了 是没人想要离开
What you fail to understand is that no one wants to.
知道人类困境的疗法是什么吗
Do you know what the cure for the human condition is?
疾病
Disease.
因为唯有如此才有寻求疗法的希望
Because only then is there hope for a cure.
我不懂
I don't understand.
多年来 我一在想保护你
For so many years, I've tried to protect you...
远离外界的污秽
from the impurities of the outside world.
但讽刺的是
But ironically, it is your friend Mr. Lockhart
我们反倒得感谢你朋友拉克哈先生
who we have to thank.
你现在是女人了
You're a woman now.
可是我生病了
But I'm not well.
我永远都会在这里照顾你
And I will always be here to take care of you.
她醒了
She's awake now.
你让我以为我有一天会离开这里
You made me believe I could leave here one day.
怎么会有人想要离开
Why would anybody wanna leave?
范海克莫
什么事
What is it?
来
Come.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这里就是你生命的起点
This is where you began.
我不想要
I don't want to.
你知道
You know...
你跟她在新婚之夜一模一样
you look just like she did on her wedding night.
她不知道
村民在那一晚把她从我身边夺走
The night they took her from me.
村民挖出胎儿并扔进含水土层
The villagers cut out the fetus and threw it in the aquifer.
那孩子没死
The child survived.
- 拜托不要 - 别怕
- Please don't. - Don't be frightened.
我们很快又是一家人了
Soon we'll be a family again.
这是我们永远的宿命
The way we were always meant to be.
没事 我妹一开始也抗拒过
It's all right. My sister was also somewhat resistant, at first.
但不久之后 她就爱上了
But after a while, she grew to like it.
我们不断努力想制造纯洁之物
We tried so many times to make something pure.
那就是你 我的爱
That something was you, my love.
现在
And now...
我们可以再度开始
we can begin again.
我等好久了
I've waited so long.
太久了
So long.
他会占据你 好吗
He will have you. Yes?
好
Yes.
你不能永远把她困在这里
You can't keep her here forever.
不能吗
No?
你觉得她到外面会变成什么样
And what do you think would become of her in your world?
一大堆你们这种人
People like you come to me in droves
带着可有可无的生活来找我
with your disposable lives.
她是你女儿
She's your daughter.
你又爱过什么了
And what have you ever loved, hmm?
你做过什么牺牲吗
What have you ever sacrificed?
这就是外面世界的贡献
This is what the outside world has to offer.
你说得对
You're right.
不要
No.
失火了
Fire. Fire!
我经营的一切都是为了她
Everything I have built has been for her.
你以为我会让你这种人渣毁了吗
You think I would let someone like you destroy that?
爸
Dad?
汉娜
Hannah.
今日探访时间已过
很壮观吧
Magnificent, isn't it?
拉克哈
Lockhart!
我们该走了
It's time to go.
- 你没事吧 - 老天
- Are you okay? - Jesus Christ.
别激动
Easy, easy.
拉克哈
Lockhart?
不会吧
My God.
你做了什么
What have you done?
潘柏呢
Where's Pembroke?
他走了
He's gone.
他走了是什么意思
What do you mean "gone"?
上车
Get in the car.
你是来办事的 记得吗
You came here to perform a task, remember?
现在给我上车
Now get in the car.
你听到我说的话了吗
Did you hear what I said?
你发疯了吗
Have you lost your mind?
其实
Actually...
我感觉我好多了
I'm feeling much better.
你搞什么想去哪
Where the hell are you going?
拉克哈 拉克哈
Lockhart! Lockhart!